Paulo Fylippe Sell Resume

Status: Telecommunications Engineer

Fields: Embedded Systems, Software Development, Signal Processing

Techs: Python, C++, Java, Matlab, Git, VHDL **Activities:** Games, Reading, Coding, Investing

Santa Catarina, Brazil paulosell.github.io sellpaulof@gmail.com +55 48 984053102

Summary

25 years old telecommunications engineer based in Santa Catarina, Brazil. I studied at the Federal Institute of Santa Catarina and my bachelor's thesis was the development of a framework for secure and reliable firmware update for embedded devices. Currently I'm working at the Embedded and Distributed Systems Laboratory at IFSC, developing the specification and the proof of concept of an embedded low-cost secure fiscal authorizing device for the state of Santa Catarina.

Experience

Software Developer / Reseacher - Federal Institute of Santa Catarina

2021 - present

- · Development of the specification and the proof of concept of an embedded low-cost secure fiscal authorizing device for the state of Santa Catarina
- · Mostly used C++ and Python

IT Analyst - Internship at NSC TV

2017 - 2018

- · Solving thecnical issues
- · Projecting improvements on the network infrastructure

Education

Graduated as Telecommunications Engineer - Federal Institute of Santa Catarina

2015 - 2021

- · Bachelor's Thesis: Secure and Reliable Firmware Update
- · Developed a framework for secure and reliable firmware update for embedded devices

Academic Experience

Research Student - Federal Institute of Santa Catarina

2020 - 2021

· Development of the specification and the proof of concept of an embedded low-cost secure fiscal authorizing device for the state of Santa Catarina

Research Student - Federal Institute of Santa Catarina

2019 - 2019

- · Worked as a research student from the LaSED (Embedded and Distributed Systems Laboratory) under the supervision of Dr. Roberto de Matos
- · Develop of a DSP block of a MDCT (Modified Discrete Cosine Transform)
- · Mostly used MatLab

Academic Tutor - Federal Institute of Santa Catarina

2018 - 2019

· Tutor of electric circuits disciplines

Fields of Knowledge

 $\cdot \mbox{Wireless communication, RF, protocol design, electric circuits, telecommunication systems, embedded devices, distributed systems.}$